This is the Rabbit R1, one of the most
controversial devices in the past few
years. But, [music] surprisingly,
because of a few recent updates, it
quietly became one of the most powerful
productivity devices on the market right
now.
>> [music]
>> And I know what you're thinking, but
this video is not sponsored. I have no
affiliation with the company at all. I
simply have just found that this
>> [music]
>> device has become an extremely useful
personal assistant. If you set it up
now, it can actually go and do stuff on
your computer, things like summarizing
[music]
videos for you, checking your email,
pretty much anything you can think of.
And the reason for that is because you
can use frontier models on this device
>> [music]
>> right now. And in using this, I've
actually found this to be an amazing
form factor. Not only is the design
super beautiful, because it's designed
by Teenage Engineering, it just makes
sense for a dedicated AI personal
assistant. You can put this on your
desk, and there's no distractions,
there's no feeds, and you can even put a
SIM card in it to replace your phone
with it. So, I'm going to get into how I
maximize the usefulness of this device,
but first,
for context, if you've never seen this
device before, this is the Rabbit R1,
like I said before, and it was released
in 2024 as an
>> [music]
>> AI-focused device. So, there were no
feeds, there were no distractions, no
keyboard. It would purely be a device
where you hit the button, you can ask it
to do something or ask it to get some
information for you, and it would just
get it back to you instantaneously.
[music] I ordered this 2 years ago, and
like many reviewers that you might have
seen before, it was really quite
disappointing. Like, it didn't really
deliver on any of its promises. [music]
The software was way too buggy, the AI
would hallucinate or not be able to
really do anything useful.
>> [music]
>> And because of that, it was actually
extremely controversial when it was
first released. So, [music] MKBHD called
it barely reviewable, and so did a bunch
of other news sites. At one point, they
also got hacked, which just kind of made
people like forget about this device,
and [music] Coffeezilla even made a
takedown video, like taking down the
company.
But, despite all that, the company
continued to ship new improvements and
improve their software and listen to
community feedback. And [music]
now, 2 years later, it's actually become
quite useful. So, I've been trying to
use it again over the past month and
surprisingly it's actually quite good.
It has come a long way. The biggest
reason why this device has become so
much more useful, despite being the same
hardware, is because AI models have
improved drastically over the past few
years. When I think about the models I
was using 2 years ago, it's basically
unusable compared to what you can get
today. So, you can integrate it with
things like Cloud Code or Open Claw or
Hermes, which are all AI assistants.
But, even besides that, one of the
reasons why I think this is underrated
as a productivity AI device is because
of the form factor. So, if you've seen
some videos on this channel, then you
probably know that I'm a fan of having
different devices for different
purposes.
>> [music]
>> And I think this is one of the best form
factors when it comes to a dedicated AI
device. There are no apps, really.
There's no feeds or distractions. And
there's only one button to control this
device, which is this push-to-talk
button. So,
you just push it, you can ask whatever
you want it to do, and then it just
responds to you. This same button also
lets you activate the camera button. So,
that also makes a lot of sense for an AI
device. Like, you'll use the camera
button to ask for different things. They
did get criticism in the past for using
like a low-resolution camera, but I
think that actually makes a lot of sense
for an AI device because you're not
trying to use the camera to take like
aesthetic photos. You're just trying to
use it to ask questions. And so, a
low-resolution camera actually makes a
lot of sense for processing speed and
also uploading [music] speed. So, the
premise of the device wasn't necessarily
wrong. It was more their execution of
the software. All the criticism, if you
look at it from 2 years ago, was
centered around their software and it
being underbaked or it being not useful.
And I think in most cases, most
companies probably just
>> [music]
>> have rolled over and died. Like during
this time, other companies like Humane
Pin, if you remember that, they
basically just got acquired and died
completely. So, I do respect that they
kept trying to improve their product
despite having every reason not to,
especially since they don't even require
a subscription fee. So, it's not like
they're even trying to retain their
customers. They already got all the
revenue. So, yeah. [music] What are the
most useful things you can do with it?
Let me just show you how it works. So,
this is the home screen for Rabbit R1.
If you slide to the right, then [music]
you have Open Claw, Cloud Code,
and you also have Hermes, which is a new
[music]
AI agent. Right now, I have all three
set up, but probably the one that I find
the most useful lately is this new one
called Hermes. [music] So,
uh if you're interested, I could also
make a video about that and how I use
Open Claw and Hermes,
but [music] let me know in the comments
below. How's the performance of my
latest YouTube video [music] on YouTube
Studio? It's going to go do that on
my computer, and let's see [music] if it
actually works.
>> July 19th, 2026, about 2.2 days ago.
Length, about 10 minutes. Performance
right now,
views [music] about 14,600 likes, 495
comments, 34 pace, 6,600 views. Day
channel, Rae Sun, [music] 251k subs
versus recent uploads.
>> Like it took 1 to 2 minutes, but you can
imagine for more complex tasks, uh this
is pretty useful. Can you go to Diary of
a CEO's
channel and summarize his latest video
and put it into my Obsidian?
All right, so it did the summary. Here
is
Alex Hormozi on Diary of a CEO, and I
can read the summary here, and it also
uh made [music] the detailed summary in
my Obsidian vault. So, yeah.
Not bad. Right now, the default way to
use Open Claw or Hermes or these
AI personal assistants is you basically
have to set up a telegram or WhatsApp
bot and you have to message them which
can be kind of like unergonomic because
it could easily get mixed in with your
other messages [music] or maybe it's
just overly technical. And if you want
to use Claude code on your phone, you
basically have to like SSH in to your
terminal and use it which can be pretty
confusing for
regular people. So with this I think
it's a lot more realistic and easy to
use as a form factor, right? Like I have
all three of them logged in connected to
my computer and I don't have to switch
through different apps just to be able
to access them. I will say that it does
feel slower using the rabbit hole in
compared to using it [music] on my phone
or directly through my computer, but I
really like how it's a dedicated pager
device
>> [music]
>> and I prefer using it over using
telegram or using the computer. And also
it's not one or the other [music] so it
doesn't disrupt any of your existing
setups or any of your existing
subscriptions. You just connect it to
this device and then you can use it
through this device. For me the most
useful thing that they added that made
this a super underrated productivity
device was the integration with these AI
agents because I can use open claw,
Hermes, I can use these frontier AI
models to basically
accomplish anything that I need and it
also doesn't require any additional
subscriptions because the device itself
doesn't have any subscriptions. They do
have their own AI called the rabbit
intern and that does come with a
subscription if you want to use it at
higher limits,
but I did try out for a bit and there
are some cool features. For example, one
thing that you could do is you could ask
it for any feature or app and then it
would just go and write code it for you.
This is the guitar app that I made with
their AI which seems to work pretty well
like
it does change the dial, but when I
tried it wasn't actually working.
Yeah, like I'm playing an E but then
it's saying it's a B.
>> [music]
>> So yeah, they did make the app, and it
does seem like it works.
Like it has a dial and everything, but
it doesn't actually work. Like when I
just tested with my guitar, it's not
actually showing me the right notes.
And so I think their own AI capabilities
is still really quite limited, and
that's pretty much my biggest criticism
with the device so far. So even though
you can use AI agents as a separate part
of the device, you can't really replace
the main AI that's on the device that
can actually control all the other
parts, like actually creating different
apps.
And their AI still feels like a super
outdated model from like 2 years ago.
It's probably like some sort of
free open-source model.
And their dictation model is also not
that good. So like um like when you're
talking into it, the transcription model
that's transcribing what you're saying
is not that good. So I find that a lot
of times it'll transcribe it
incorrectly.
And luckily, because I'm using like a
frontier model, it'll realize that I
said it incorrectly and then correct
itself.
But sometimes I I'll have to speak
slowly for the Rabbit R1 to actually
pick up what I'm saying accurately. And
I think that's a shame because AI models
with transcription has really come a
long way over the past few years. Like
if you use Super Whisper, like I talked
about on the channel before, or Whisper
Flow, you can pretty much whisper and
speak at full speed and even mumble, and
it'll get it almost 99% perfectly in any
language. [music]
So I think if they just let you switch
it out for a different voice model that
streams in real time,
>> [music]
>> it would at least make this device two
times better. They did add that feature
I showed earlier where you can use a
keyboard to type your request, uh which
is useful sometimes, but I find that the
screen is really too small to
to type on this. So uh I don't really
use the keyboard at [music] all.
But nevertheless, I still think that
this is a pretty underrated productivity
AI device that you can use as a personal
assistant. Using this and having this on
my desk really makes me think about what
the future of our devices will look
like. Especially with Siri AI being more
integrated on the OS level or Open AI
coming out with their own AI device
later this year or next year.
Like it would make sense to me that we
would have something like this or
something in the movie Her where
>> [music]
>> there's really no need for apps. Like we
can just
ask for the things that we need and then
they'll just show it to us. But anyways,
that's it for this video. Let me know
what you thought of this device, whether
or not you try it, and if you use
>> [music]
>> AI assistants like Open Claw Hermes. If
you're interested, I can make a video
about my setup with Open Claw Hermes and
what I use it for that has
really improved my life over the past
few months. So yeah, see you in the
comments [music] and catch you in the
next video. Let's get it.
>> [music]